welcome to another installment of the
riot JS and redux video series if
you haven't been following along it will
probably be much easier to start at the
beginning since each video building
where the previous video that staff and
remember to get up to speed on Redux
itself you really can't be there had I O
videos by redox as creator Dan Abrams us
when we left off last time we had added
the ability to add a news has to our
list but a task list really isn't very
useful for can check things off so this
time we're going to look at adding check
boxes and updating our items so the
first thing we're gonna do is we're
gonna go into our task list ID tag file
and we're gonna add an input to each
item in early and that's how it will be
a checkbox never gonna give it and I D
task that I D so we'll take the idea
value that comes back for API will use
that as our input elements I D actually
gonna add a checked attribute I'm gonna
pass that an expression and value that
expression is going to be task that is
complete and at this point we don't have
any is complete properties are tasks so
those all the defaults to false and a
check boxes will not be checked so at
this stage we can go into your browser
then we can refresh each other items
should show up with the checkbox
checkbox is going to do anything yet
let's go back into task list and I want
to add on changes to the input and I'm
gonna give that a value of handle check
which is a function will create right
here in our task list file so I had some
script X and handle check which is going
to accept the event we're gonna have
this function call this top stud handle
check which is going to be a function
its past 10 from our to-do app tag
you're gonna pass the events target dot
I D which is gonna get the idea
attribute of the check box and a boolean
value that tells this handle check
function whether this is checked or
unchecked you know it's going to the to
do at tank
and we're gonna add a handle task
completion change function and that's
going to accept an idea and a flag
holder is complete and in that function
I'm gonna call stored at dispatch
actions . Tuggle complete and I'm gonna
pass along the idea and the is complete
boolean value that this action doesn't
exist yet we'll get to that moment in
our task list haag we want to pass in
the handle check attribute Thanksgiving
a reference to the function we just
created said this is going to wire up
our check box change event to passer to
this function which will then handled
the store dispatch call so in actions
that Jas we're gonna scroll to the
bottom and we're gonna at Otago complete
action creator
except except that I T is complete and
total complete is going to return a
function as a Redux don't function so
it's good except dispatching get state
as arguments in this function we're
gonna do an XHR request and for this
request rather than doing it put in
passing the entire task action we're
gonna call patch and we're gonna call
patch against the URL that specific to
the task that we're changing and we're
going to pass an updated value for is
complete so this is gonna have to be a
call to look at those three thousand /
tasks / whatever our task ideas so in
order to accomplish that we could
concatenate the string by calling
localhost 3,000 task and and just using
the + operator to add the idea value
that's passenger function on to the end
of that URL but a better option is to
use the ES 2015 stranger police and
simpler syntax so we're gonna wrap our
string impact X I'm gonna pants in this
dollar signed double curly briefs and
then inside the curly braces we can pass
in RI devalue so we pass and I D which
comes from the functions arguments in
here and this is going to create our
string that are mapped to localhost /
tasks
/ one or two or whatever that I D value
is now that we have that setup we also
need our request content type better so
we're passing content aight applications
/ JSON and we'll set up a request onload
function to handle the response from
this request and we send a request
we're gonna pass that Jason that string
if I almost Ring of Fire an object that
has our is complete property with her is
complete value and in our onload
function Aladdin if statement so that we
can respond properly to successful
requests and we get a successful request
for going to dispatch an action and that
action is going to be completely changed
and we're gonna pass along the I D and
the is complete Boolean we don't have a
complete change the action created yet
so let's create it so create function
complete change will pass an idea and is
complete and incomplete change is gonna
reach her in action object with a type
test completion changed the data
property with an object that represents
our task updates or have the task I D
and that new is complete value now that
our action creator set up let's update
or juicer to handle this case back into
indexed ijs travel at a case for the
test completion changed action and this
one's gonna be a little more complicated
than what we've done so far because we
need to take a specific item out of the
list update it and return to bring in
new state that represents the existing
state with that change in its original
place so the first thing we're gonna do
is we're going to use the past and I D
from action that data and we're going to
get the tasks index in our tasks array
so create a variable task index and
we're gonna sign it to state that test .
find index keep in mind that fine index
isn't necessarily supported on all
browsers depends on what you have to
support but you can grab a utility
library such as low dash where there
will be an alternative that will provide
the same functionality find indexes
going to take a function and that's
going to go through our task array the
first time that function returns a true
that will be the index the country
and now that we have the task index need
to create a new array with the updated
task in its original place and that
updated task has to have its new is
complete value so we're gonna start by
creating the new tasks are ranked I'm
going to start with a call to state that
tasks dots lace we're gonna pass lights
0 and our task index with this is gonna
do is return a new array with the values
from 0 up to the index from our current
tests so far task index is zero just
return an empty array and then we're
going to use can can to add are updated
task into disarray and then we're going
to use another call to concat to add the
rest of the rates of the end so the
second can catch call will cost eight
that has such slice and basically from
one after the task index to the end of
the Iraq for our target item we're gonna
use object that a sign I wanna take the
item from our tests array
our target index and we're going to
merge it with our is complete property
into a new object and that gets passed
back into can cat so there's new tasks
array will represent our newly updated
so that takes care of our to-do items
two and three and at the end of
everything we want to take our entire
state merged into a new object with the
updated tasks array and returned that
former reducer and to make sure this can
run I'm gonna go back to actions that
Jas and I'm gonna expose our action
creator
exports that title complete your browser
and refresh
should be able to update and we'll see
JSON that it's added that is complete
flag to both items they were checked
they go back to the browser and uncheck
one of those items I can see again that
the update took place now we have this
working but there's a better way to rate
this code so let's go back to a reducer
and censoring our code through battle
with Webtech we can take advantage of
some syntax that'll make this look a
little bit nicer so let's get rid of our
comments just a clean this up a bit and
I want to take my call to new tasks
where I'm using canned cat and I'm gonna
come in town so we had it for reference
and I'm gonna create a new variable new
tasks and I'm gonna set at equanimity
Iraq and inside that a rayon gonna make
my same call to state that has taught
slice from in Dec 02 whatever might ask
indexes and I'm going to tack on three
periods to the beginning of that this is
the spread operator so this basically
says take whatever this array is and
spread it out into its individual values
so my rail now have individual items
returned from test that slice and then
my next year will be my updated item
based on task index and I can use that
spread operator one more time to attack
the items from the rest of the array
into this new Iraq into work with either
code I prefer this I think it's a little
more concise little bit easier to read
and if we go back to our browser we can
verify that this still works I just
check all the items and take a look at
D-day jason is complete has been created
and Mark true on all of this I don't
to go back into the browser I can set
the item's caused by unchecking the code
and just keep the new refactored version
of new tasks so far we've only focus on
the happy path when everything goes
right with our API you should handle
errors for all of your API calls but
we're going to focus on an error that
occurs when we mark an item complete and
we get an error back from the server and
the reason we're going to look at this
one specifically is that is a check the
box and there's some kind of error on
the server
the update is gonna happen we're not
going to update or Steve but the check
box is gonna remain checked so we need
to uncheck the checkbox if we get an
error back just to make sure that are
you I actually represents the state of
our application based on a response from
the server so I'm gonna use a tool
called Charles that will allow me to
basically fake a 500 error from the
server setting up charles is little bit
outside the scope of this video but
maybe I'll do one in the future but for
now I'm just gonna open up my console
and I set it up so that I get an error
when I check the box on record video and
you'll see that I get a 500 error back
from this patch when that happens both
when I check it when I am so we need to
update our producer I'm sorry we need
out there action creator to account for
this error and reset the UI to represent
the current state of the application so
I'm going to actions that Jas and in my
title complete function
hadn't else to this if statement and in
my else I'm going to dispatch the same
complete changed action that I dispatch
from the successful response but I'm
going to negate the value of is complete
and it's basically go through update my
state and forced the tagged refresh so
that my check box instead of remaining
checked
unchecked itself in the case of an era
let's take a look at that in the browser
so we still have Charles running the
fakers 500 error refresh to make sure my
updated JavaScript is loaded when I
check record video see that I get an
error but it's also dispatched you might
ask employees changed but then when it
is completed fast and the check boxes
and checked immediately after checking
it now this isn't super user friendly
whoever check that checkbox has no idea
what has happened so let's add an error
message so to do that first thing I'm
going to do is going to go into Maytag
directory and I'm gonna create a new
file error message that tank and as with
any tags I'll going to create a route
tags and myself put our message was
clear that in a div we're going to get
our message through an attribute on the
tag when we reference it so called this
message and we need an attribute to
control our visibility so throw a show
attribute on the div and we're gonna
need to pass something into that
expression will also create an attribute
when we reference the tag cloud is error
and that would get us through this stops
so it's had this error message tag to
our to do at tank and we're gonna need
to give that a message attribute for now
was hard code test message in there just
to make sure this is working and we're
also gonna need the is era and will pass
this true for now so that displays when
we tested and make sure that works let's
go to our index ijs file and add require
statement and now there should be
included in our bundle let's go back to
the browser refresh your page and we
should see our error message tag being
displayed because we hard coded in our
message and our visibility at review so
let's make it work for real so in our
actions digest file
we're gonna add an action creator called
show error and show airs going to accept
a message and we're gonna return an
object with the type show error and a
dad of property with the value of the
message so I went to handle this show
error action in our reducer so let's go
back to index IHS and inner reducer will
add a case for the show air action and
in this case will return object that
assign their existing state plus an
object that has or is there an error
message properties merged into a new
object returned as our updated state and
now that our producer set up to handle
this let's go into our to-do app tank
update is hard coded values that we put
in sort of place our message with an
expression expression is going to take
this done state error message and we
have crews are hard coded value for his
error at your place that with a call in
this state is error and WeatherTech
properly configured let's go back to
actions such a US and update our toggle
complete action creator to dispatch our
show error action so this patch show air
and will pass in the value eighty-eight
error and let's take a look at that back
in the browser and go to refresh their
error message tag should be hidden by
the phone and I'm gonna check on record
video and I'm gonna get my 500 error
back its gonna show my error message
will check back stays where it was good
except now the error just stays forever
let's take care of that setback and
actions that Jas gonna create an action
creator Haider message so create an
empty function high terror and this is
going to return an action object with
the type property of high terror expose
high terror on our exports to the TAV
actions that Jas will add the hider
function as part of the export and as
always we need to handle this case in a
reducer so the back to index ijs
and I'm going to add a case for high
terror we're gonna handle that case
buries her earning an updated version of
the state and this time we said is there
a false on error message to an empty
string
gonna go into the error message tag I'm
going to wire up hyperlinked that will
trigger hiding the message so as any
traffic goes nowhere with a non click
handler points to a function called hide
message will add the hyde message
function to a set of script at the
bottom of arabists tag number to call
this dot dot dot hide and hide is going
to be a function that's passed into the
error message tag from to-do app
to back in to do a tank will add height
error message function and Haider
message will call stored at dispatch and
Cassidy and actions . high terror so now
we need to pass this in as our height
attribute on the error message tank go
back up here by our height attribute
pass in Hyderabad message and we can go
back to our browser refresh the trigger
that error you get my message you'll see
that I have my link here and click that
and it hurts my message so let's take
the Saracen area one step further and
make this is slightly better experience
for end user rather than forcing them to
click the X to get out of the error
message will hide it after a set amount
of time to do that we're going to go
into action such a yes we're going to
add a new async action Creator will call
that temporary message and will have to
accept message has an argument
other racing action creators return a
function that accepts dispatch get state
as arguments and we're gonna call
dispatch show air we're gonna pass the
message through and now to handle hiding
the error message or an asset timeout
timeout to one second hand in that
setTimeout we're gonna call dispatch to
higher error now only get an error
message to show up immediately and after
a second message should be hidden if we
haven't been there already and now has
replaced our call to show error with a
called a temporary message so in our
toggle complete function where we get
the error response replace that dispatch
and call temporary message instead show
error and if we go into a browser and
refresh we should be able to click
Record a video message and after a
second goes by where messages to Spears
thank you for watching